Paul Henry Sheats Papers
Paul Henry Sheats Papers
- Subject files
  - Participation studies, 1950s-1960s (Box 60)
  - Population
    - Agency for International Development, 1972 (Box 60)
    - California, 1960s (Box 60)
    - California, 1960s (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 61)
  - Program planning
    - American Association for the United Nations, 1940s (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940s-1970s (Box 61)
  - Psychology of adults, 1940s-1960s (Box 61)
  - Public school
    - Bibliography, 1967 (Box 61)
    - California
      - Administration, 1960s (Box 61)
      - California Council for Adult Education, 1971 (Box 61)
      - Citizen Unity Committee and the former Morale Committee of the Schenectady County Consolidated County War Council, 1942-1943 (Box 61)
      - Handbook, 1973 (Box 61)
      - Salaries, 1950s; 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Statements, 1967-1969 (Box 61)
      - Studies, 1940s-1960s (Box 62)
      - Teacher Training, 1950s-1960s (Box 62)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940s-1960s (Box 62)
      - Los Angeles
        - Annual Reports, 1950s-1960s (Box 62)
        - Belmont Community Adult School, 1960s (Box 62)
        - Counseling, 1958 (Box 62)
        - Curriculum, 1968-1969 (Box 62)
        - Division of Career and Continuing Education, 1970s (Box 62)
        - Division of Career and Continuing Education (cont.), 1970s (Box 63)
        - Evaluations, 1960s-1970s (Box 63)
        - Gerontology Office, 1950s-1960s (Box 63)
        - Goals, 1968 (Box 63)
        - Handbooks, 1971 (Box 63)
        - Studies, 1950s-1960s (Box 63)
        - West Valley Occupational Center, n.d., undated (Box 63)
        - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 63)
    - Curriculum (Box 64)
    - Illinois, 1966 (Box 64)
    - National Association for Public Continuing and Adult Education
      - Administrative Swap Shot, 1970-1974; v. 17, no. 2-5; v. 18, no. 1-5; v. 19, no. 1, 3; v. 20, no. 1-6; v. 21, no. 1, 2 (Box 64)
      - Almanac, 1974 (Box 64)
      - Pulse of Public Continuing and Adult Education, 1970-1974; v. 11, no. 3, 4, 8; v. 12, no. 1, 2, 4-7; v. 13, no. 4-7; v. 14, no. 1-3, 5, 6, 8; v. 15, no. 2 (Box 64)
      - Techniques for Teachers of Adults, 1974-1975; v. 15, no. 2, 3, 5, 6 (Box 64)
    - National Association of Public School Adult Educators, 1950s (Box 64)
    - National Education Association, 1950s (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 64)
  - Religious education
    - Indiana University - Purdue University, 1954 (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 64)
  - Research
    - American Educational Research Association
      - Directories, 1969; 1974-1975 (Box 64)
      - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 64)
    - Antioch College, 1959-1960 (Box 64)
    - Knox, Alan B., 1960s (Box 65)
    - Kreitlow, Burton W., 1960s (Box 65)
    - Mountain Plains Region, 1967-1971 (Box 65)
    - Stanford University, 1966 (Box 65)
    - University of California, 1963 (Box 65)
    - Washington University
      - University College Research Publications, 1966; no. 9, 10 (Box 65)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 65)
  - Residential education
    - Bibliography, 1968 (Box 66)
    - Directories, 1960s (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 66)
  - Science and technology, 1960s-1970s (Box 66)
  - Socio-technical systems, 1960s-1970s (Box 66)
  - Staff development
    - Bibliography, 1973 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 66)
  - Teacher training, 1940s-1970s; 2 folders (Box 66)
    See also Subject files: Adult Basic Education
  - Testing
    - College Entrance Examination Board, 1960s-1970s (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 66)
  - University extension
    - History and overview, 1920s-1970s; 3 folders (Box 67)
    - Administration, 1950s-1960s (Box 67)
    - Cooperative extension, 1950s-1970s (Box 67)
    - Policy statements, 1960s (Box 67)
    - Professional upgrading, 1960s (Box 67)
    - Programs and faculty participation, 1950s (Box 67)
    - Title I Programs, 1960s-1970s (Box 67)
    - [California] University of California, 1940s-1950s (Box 67)
    - Florida Board of Regents, 1967 (Box 68)
    - Florida Institute for Continuing University Studies, 1963 (Box 68)
    - [Illinois] University of Chicago, 1892-1930 (Box 68)
    - Indiana, 1961 (Box 68)
    - Iowa, 1961 (Box 68)
    - Michigan, 1951; 1970 (Box 68)
    - [Missouri ] University of Missouri, 1967 (Box 68)
    - New Jersey Association for Adult Education, 1963 (Box 68)
    - [New Jersey] Rutgers State University, 1950s-1960s (Box 68)
    - [New York] City College, 1970s (Box 68)
    - New York University, 1966-1967 (Box 68)
    - [New York] University of the State of New York Bulletin, 1 Dec 1948; no. 1357 (Box 68)
    - Oregon, 1966-1968 (Box 68)
    - [Virginia] University of Virginia, 1944 (Box 68)
    - Washington, undated (Box 68)
    - [Wisconsin] University of Wisconsin, 1950s (Box 68)
  - Urban extension, 1950s-1960s (Box 68)
  - Urban extension, 1960s-1970s (Box 69)
  - Vocational Education
    See also Subject files: Labor education.
    - B'nai B'rith Career and Counseling Services
      - Explorations, parts 1 and 2, 1974 (Box 69)
      - Resources, 1974 (Box 69)
    - Chartering Process
      - Report, 1968 (Box 69)
      - Instructional Manual, 1968 (Box 69)
    - National Advisory Council on Vocational Education, 1960s-1970s (Box 69)
    - Panel of Consultants on Vocational Education
      - Report, 1963 (Box 69)
      - Summary Report, 1963 (Box 69)
      - Appendix 1, 3, 1963 (Box 70)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, 1960s-1970s; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 70)
  - Women
    - Bibliography, 1967 (Box 70)
    - College of San Mateo, 1970 (Box 70)
    - Radcliffe Institute, 1968 (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1970s (Box 70)
  - World education
    - International Congress of University Adult Education, 1962 (Box 70)
    - International Council for Adult Education, 1975 (Box 70)
    - World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession
      - Echo, 1971-1975; v. 20, no. 2; v. 21, no. 2-4; v. 22, no. 1-4; v. 23, no. 1, 3 (Box 70)
    - World Education Inc., 1974 (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 71)
  - World War II
    - Office of War Information, 1940s; 4 folders (Box 71)
    - Office of War Information (legal size), 1940s (Box 91)
- Geographical files
  - Africa, 1960s-1970s (Box 71)
  - Australia
    - Aborigines, 1969-1970 (Box 71)
    - Australian Association of Adult Education, 1960s-1970s (Box 71)
    - Australian National University, 1960s-1970s (Box 72)
    - Australian National University (legal size), 1960s-1970s (Box 91)
    - Canberra University College, 1950s-1960s (Box 72)
    - Council of Adult Education, 1940s-1970s (Box 72)
    - Duncan, W. G. K.
      - Adult Education in Australia, 1944 (Box 91)
      - Appendices A-H, 1944 (Box 91)
      - Appendices J-R, and Index, 1944 (Box 91)
      - Adult Education in New South Wales, 1944 (Box 91)
    - Kormilda College, 1969-1970 (Box 72)
    - Special Schools Bulletin, 1968-1971; v. 5, no. 6; v. 6, no. 2-5; v. 7, no. 2-6; v. 8, no. 1; (Box 72)
    - Tasmania Adult Education Board, 1950s-1970s (Box 72)
    - University of Adelaide. Department of Adult Education.
      - Annual Reports, 1950s-1960s (Box 72)
      - Pamphlets, 1950s-1960s (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 72)
    - University of Melbourne, 1950s (Box 73)
    - University of New England, 1950s-1970s (Box 73)
    - University of New England (legal size), 1950s-1960s (Box 91)
    - University of Queensland, 1968; 1970 (Box 73)
    - University of Sydney
      - Aboriginal Family Education Centers, 1969-1971 (Box 73)
      - Department of Adult Education, 1968-1970 (Box 73)
      - Department of Tutorial Classes, 1950s (Box 73)
      - Extension Board, 1950s (Box 73)
    - University of Western Australia, 1950s-1970s (Box 73)
    - University of Western Australia (legal size), 1950s-1960s (Box 92)
    - Wangaratta Centre for Continuing Education, 1970 (Box 73)
    - Wangaratta Centre for Continuing Education (legal size), 1960s-1970s (Box 92)
    - Workers' Educational Association, 1950s; 1970s; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous (legal size), 1950s-1960s (Box 92)
  - Brazil, 1961
  - Canada
    - Canadian Association for Adult Education
      - Bibliographies, 1950s-1970s (Box 74)
      - Learning for Living, 1950s; no. 1-7, 10, 11; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1960s (Box 74)
    - Canadian Institute of Adult Education, 1966-1967 (Box 75)
    - Center for Community Studies, 1950s-1960s (Box 75)
    - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education
      - Bibliography, 1971 (Box 75)
      - Comparative studies, 1971 (Box 75)
      - Degree research, 1968-1969 (Box 75)
      - Non-degree research, 1960s-1970s (Box 75)
      - Women, 1969 (Box 75)
    - McGill University, 1969-1970 (Box 75)
    - St. Francis Xavier University, 1955 (Box 75)
    - Thomas More Institute, 1960s (Box 76)
    - University of British Columbia
      - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 76)
      - Occasional Papers in Continuing Education, 1968-1973; no. 1-8 (Box 76)
      - Niemi, John A., 1970s (Box 76)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (Box 76)
    - University of Lethbridge, 1960s (Box 76)
      See also Personal files: University of Lethbridge Consultation
    - University of Montreal, 1960s (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1970s; 2 folders (Box 77)
  - China, 1960s-1970s (Box 77)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1967 (Box 77)
  - Denmark, 1930s-1960s (Box 77)
  - Europe
    - European Bureau of Adult Education Notes and Studies, 1957-1966; 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940s-1960s (Box 78)
  - Finland, 1968 (Box 78)
  - France
    - Centre Universitaire de Coopération Économique et Sociale Centre
      - Activity Report, 1970 (Box 78)
      - Programs, 1960s-1970s (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 78)
  - Germany
    - Bibliography, 1969 (Box 78)
    - Volkshochschulen, 1950s-1960s (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930s-1950s; 2 folders (Box 79)
  - Greece, 1957; 1960s; 3 folders (Box 79)
  - Hong Kong, 1960s (Box 79)
  - Hungary, circa 1968 (Box 79)
  - India
    - Association of Voluntary Agencies for Rural Development, 1960-1961 (Box 79)
    - National Fundamental Education Centre, 1958; 1960 (Box 79)
    - National Fundamental Education Centre (legal size), 1961 (Box 92)
    - University of Rajasthan
      - News, 1967; 1968-1969; v. 5, no. 3; v. 6, no. 1, 2; v. 7, no. 1-4 (Box 80)
      - Reports, 1960s (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940s-1960s (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous (legal size), 1950s-1960s (Box 92)
  - Israel, 1950s-1970s (Box 80)
  - Italy, 1950s-1960s (Box 80)
  - Japan, 1950s-1960s (Box 80)
  - Kenya
    - Board of Adult Education, 1971 (Box 80)
    - Kenya Journal of Adult Education, 1972-1974; v. 1, no. 1; v. 2, no. 2; v. 3, no. 1, 4 (Box 80)
  - Korea, 1960-1961 (Box 81)
  - Latin America, 1960s-1970s (Box 81)
  - Liberia, 1965 (Box 81)
  - Middle East, 1960s-1970s (Box 81)
  - Nepal, n.d. (Box 81)
  - Netherlands
    - International Bulletin of the Leidsche Onderwijsinstellingen-Leiden-Holland, 1965-1970 (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 81)
  - New Zealand
    - Auckland Headmasters' Association, 1960s-1970s (Box 81)
    - Council of Adult Education, 1959 (Box 92)
    - National Council of Adult Education
      - Annual Reports, 1955-1973 (Box 81)
      - Newsletters, 1966-1970 (Box 81)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 81)
    - University of Auckland, 1960s-1970s (Box 92)
    - Victoria University of Wellington, 1950s-1970s; 3 folders (Box 82)
    - Victoria University of Wellington (legal size), 1969-1970 (Box 92)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s; 3 folders (Box 82)
  - Nigeria, 1960s-1970s (Box 82)
  - Norway, 1950s-1960s (Box 82)
  - Philippines
    - Community school, 1952 (Box 82)
    - Family planning, 1970s (Box 83)
    - Fulbright Program, 1940s-1950s (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940s; 1960s (Box 83)
  - South Africa
    - Apartheid, 1950s (Box 83)
    - Institute of Citizenship, 1950s (Box 83)
    - University of Cape Town, 1950s (Box 83)
    - University of South Africa, 1959 (Box 83)
  - South East Asia, 1942 (Box 83)
  - Sweden, 1930s-1970s (Box 83)
  - Taiwan, 1950s-1960s (Box 83)
  - Tanzania
    - Institute of Adult Education - Dar Es Salaam
      - Studies in Adult Education, 1973-1974; no. 5, 8-10, 16, 18 (Box 84)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1970s (Box 84)
      - Miscellaneous (legal size), 1960s-1970s (Box 92)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 84)
  - Thailand
    - International Workshop for Evaluation Specialist on Non-Formal Education for Functional Literacy and Family Life Planning, 1974; 2 folders (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1970s (Box 84)
  - Turkey, 1950s-1960s (Box 84)
  - U.S.S.R., 1950s-1960s (Box 84)
  - United Kingdom
    - Edinburgh University, 1960s (Box 84)
    - National Foundation for Adult Education, 1947-1948 (Box 84)
    - National Institute of Adult Education, 1950s-1960s (Box 84)
    - National Institute of Adult Education (legal size), 1960s (Box 92)
    - Ruskin College, 1950s-1960s (Box 85)
    - Universities Council for Adult Education, 1960s (Box 85)
    - University of Birmingham, 1960s (Box 85)
    - University of Glasgow, 1960s (Box 85)
    - University of Keele, 1960s (Box 85)
    - University of London, 1960s (Box 85)
    - University of Manchester, 1960s-1970s (Box 85)
    - University of Oxford - Delegacy for Extra-Mural Studies
      - Annual Reports, 1955-1957; 1960,; 1965-1966 (Box 85)
      - Rewley House Papers, 1956-1966; v. 3, no. 5, 6, 8-10; v. 4, no. 1-3; 3 folders (Box 85)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 92)
    - University of Nottingham, 1960s (Box 92)
    - Workers Educational Association, 1940s-1960s (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1960s; 3 folders (Box 86)
  - Uruguay, 1969 (Box 86)
  - West Indies, 1950s-1960s (Box 86)
  - Yugoslavia, 1962 (Box 86)
- Printed material
  See also Organizational records series above, which includes significant printed material.
  - About Adult Education in Los Angeles, ed. by Gloria Houston, 1971 (Box 86)
  - Adult and Continuing Education Today, 1974-1975; v. 4, no. 24; v. 5, no. 2 (Box 86)
  - Adult Education Association of the U.S.A.
    - Adult Education Monographs, 1956-1958; no. 1, 2, 4 (Box 86)
    - Articles, 1955; 1957,; 1968 (Box 86)
    - Dateline, 1974; v. 1, no. 5, 7 (Box 86)
    - Federal Support for Adult Education Directory, 1966 (Box 86)
  - Adult Education Defined and Described, by Wayne L. Schroeder, circa 1970 (Box 86)
  - Adult Education Process and Procedure, by Paul Bergevin, John McKinley and Robert M. Smith, 1961 (Box 87)
  - Adult Education Services of State Departments of Education, by John B. Holden, 1959 (Box 87)
  - Adult Educators of Greater Los Angeles
    - Open Channels, 1971-1975; v. 1, no. 4; v. 2, no. 2, 4; v. 3, no. 5, 7; v. 6, no. 1 (Box 87)
  - American Council on Education
    - Fact Book on Higher Education, 1963 (Box 87)
  - California
    - Senate Interim Committee on Adult Education
      - Partial Report, 1951 (Box 87)
      - 11th Report, 1953 (Box 87)
    - State Department of Education Bulletin, 1942; 1951,; 1953-1955,; 1957; v. 11, no. 2; v. 20, no. 4; v. 22, no. 6; v. 23, no. 5; v. 24, no. 8, 16; v. 26, no. 12, 13; 2 folders (Box 87)
    - Handbook on Adult Education in California, Rev. Ed., 1966 (Box 87)
  - California Going, Going...: Our State's Struggle to Remain Beautiful and Productive, by Samuel E. Wood and Alfred E. Heller, 1962 (Box 87)
  - Commission of Professors of Adult Education
    - Adult Education: A New Imperative for Our Times, 1961 (Box 87)
  - Comparative Adult Education, Bibliography and Resources (Box 87)
  - Continuing Education and the Problem of Excellence, by John B. Schwertman, 1955 (Box 87)
  - Coordinating Council for Higher Education, 1960s; reports; 3 folders (Box 88)
  - Cross Cultural Interaction Skills: A Digest of Recent Recent Training Literature, by Roger DeCrow, 1969 (Box 88)
  - Educational Alternatives: Crisis in the Hemisphere, by Thomas J. LaBelle, circa 1971 (Box 88)
  - Educational Strategies for the 1970s, by Philip H. Coombs (Box 88)
  - Environmental Quality and the Citizen: A Teaching Guide for Adult Education Courses Related to the Environment, by Bernard L. Clausen and Ross L. Iverson, [1972] (Box 88)
  - Field of Adult Education and Implicit Functions for the Division of Adult Education, 1969 (Box 88)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, 1973; v. 4, no. 2 (Box 88)
  - Global Dimensions in U.S. Education: The Community, by William C. Rogers, 1972
  - Hospital Personnel Development: A Manual for Trainers, 1967; drafts, Chapters 2-5 (Box 88)
  - Identifying Educational Needs of Adults, by Homer Kempfer, 1951 (Box 88)
  - Improving Your English Skills, by Leonard S. Bennett, et al., 1974 (Box 88)
  - Invitation to Learning, 1952; v. 2, no. 1 (Box 88)
  - Landmarks and New Horizons in Continuing Education, 1971; no. 1 (Box 88)
  - National Advisory Council on Adult Education
    - Federal Activities in Support of Adult Education, 1972 (Box 88)
    - National Organizations and Voluntary Associations With Adult Education Concerns in the United States, 1971 (Box 88)
    - Reports, 1971-1973 (Box 89)
    - State Demographic Data, 1973 (Box 89)
  - National Education Association. Division of Adult Education Service.
    - Staff Papers, 1970 (Box 89)
  - New York Adult Education Council
    - "Adult Education for Everybody", 1954 (Box 89)
    - 20th Anniversary Yearbook of Adult Education, 1953 (Box 89)
  - Next 30 Years: Concepts, Methods and Anticipations, by F. E. Emery, circa late 1960s (Box 89)
  - Noncredit Activities in Institutions of Higher Education: Registrations by Florence B. Kemp, 1967-1968; 1972 (Box 89)
  - North Carolina State University at Raleigh, Department of Adult and Community Education
    - Bibliography of Doctoral Dissertations, 1967-1974 (Box 89)
  - Practice of Public Relations: Case Studies by 20 Professionals, ed. by Dr. Kenneth Owler Smith, 1968 (Box 89)
  - Selected Approaches to Adult Education, by Homer Kempfer and Grace S. Wright, 1950 (Box 89)
  - Social Action in Social Studies: Toward a Rationale, by Fred M. Newmann, 1972 (Box 89)
  - Syracuse University, University College, 1950s-1960s; speeches (Box 89)
  - Texas
    - Continuing Education: Thrust for Relevance Proposed State Plan for Adult and Continuing Education, 2nd draft, 1974 (Box 89)
  - Trans-action, 1964-1965; v. 1, no. 4-6; v. 2, no. 1, 2, 4-6; v. 3, no. 1; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - United States Department of the Interior, Office of Education
    - Bulletin, 1932; no. 12 (Box 89)
  - University of California at Riverside
    - Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 90)
  - University of Chicago
    - Continuing Education Report, 1965-1967; 1969; nos. 1-16, 19 (Box 90)
  - University of Missouri
    - President's Committee on Communication, Abridged Report, 1968 (Box 90)
  - University of Southern California
    - "Status Report on the Organization and Functions of the College of Continuing Education", 1974 (Box 90)
  - World Education Inc.
    - Evaluation Report, 1973 (Box 90)
  - Youth as Socio-Cultural Systems in American Society, by Thomas J. Labelle, 1972 (Box 90)
- Recordings
  - The People Act, Episode 9: Farm Families Organize to Create a Real Community / The People Act, Episode 10: A Lumber Area Maps Out a New Future, sheats_ph_001; 1 phonodisc, 33 1/3 rpm
  - The Ways of Mankind, Episode 7: Legend of the Long House / The Ways of Mankind, Episode 8: You Are Not Alone, sheats_ph_002; 1 phonodisc, 33 1/3 rpm